Guide to the Michael Lerner Collection on MAD Magazine research, 1951-2005 SPEC.CGA.MLM
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
- Articles, 1951-2005
  - Articles in Publications, 1951-2000
    - Pipe Line, "What- Me Collect?", April 1995 (Box MLM 18, Item 6)
      The MAd and EC Collectibles Guide
    - Pipes and Tobaccos, "The Lighter Side of Dave Berg", Sprin 1998 (Box MLM 18, Item 7)
      Interview with MAd Magazine's Dave Berg
    - Playboy, December 1957 (Box MLM 18, Item 8)
      Harvey Kurtzman article
    - Playboy, February 1960 (Box MLM 18, Item 9)
      Harvey Hurtzman article
    - Playboy, Ocotber 1962 (Box MLM 18, Item 10)
      First Annie Fanny cartoon
    - Popular Science, "No Hear This IBM 704", March 1961 (Box MLM 18, Item 11)
      Article about computers with Alfred E. Neuman's face being printed out
    - Postcard Collector, " The Man for MAD", August 1987 (Box MLM 18, Item 12)
      Collecting postcards with omages of the pre-MAD Alfred E. Neuman
    - Postcrypt, Spring 1996 (Box MLM 18, Item 13)
      Tales from the Crypt
    - Previews Primo, August 1998 (Box MLM 18, Item 14)
      Advertisement for Alfred E. Neuman action figure
    - Preview, "What, Me Art?, November 6, 1992 (Box MLM 26, Item 5)
      MAD Magazine exhibition in Artspace gallery, Raleigh, N.C.
    - Previews, August 1998 (Box MLM 19, Item 1)
    - Previews, December 1998 (Box MLM 19, Item 2)
    - Previews, May 1999 (Box MLM 19, Item 3)
    - Previews, December 1999 (Box MLM 19, Item 4)
    - Publisher's Weekly, "When is Parody Plagiarism?", December 30, 1963 (Box MLM 19, Item 5)
      Article about Irving Berlin lawsuit against MAD
    - Publisher's Weekly, "Parady and Satire Deserve Substantial Freedom", October 5, 1964 (Box MLM 19, Item 6)
      Article relating to Irving Berlin and MAD lawsuit
    - Publisher's Weekly, "Don't Get Even, Get MAD", January 10, 1986 (Box MLM 20, Item 1)
      Article by Lyle Stewart, former buisness manager of MAD with overview of comic book censorship and start of the Comic Book Code Authoirty
    - Publisher's Weekly, September 19, 1994 (Box MLM 20, Item 2)
      Brief article with photograph of new D. Debartolo book "Good Days and MAD."
    - Reader's Digest, "Comic Books- Blueprints for Delinquency", May 1954 (Box MLM 20, Item 3)
      Excerpts from "Suduction of the Innocent" by Fredric Wertham, M.D.
    - Reader's Digest, "Progress in Cleaning Up the Comics", February 1956 (Box MLM 20, Item 4)
      MAD mistakenly called a "thriller." Letter attacking this article appear in MAD # 28, including an apology from the author.
    - The Realist, Autumn 1992 (Box MLM 20, Item 5)
      Issue dedicated to William Gaines. MAD and EC cover tribute
    - Reflex, "Don Martin: Not MAD, but still Cracked", January 1993 (Box MLM 20, Item 6)
      Howard Chaykin interview with Don Martin; with illustrations.
    - Roctober, Fall 1998 (Box MLM 20, Item 7)
    - Rolling Stone, July 10, 1980 (Box MLM 26, Item 6)
      Norman Mingo Obituary
    - Rolling Stone, "What, Me Rock?", October 18, 1990 (Box MLM 26, Item 7)
      Sidebar article about MAD rock parodies.
    - Rolling Stone, "William M. Gaines", August 6, 1992 (Box MLM 26, Item 8)
      William Gaines tribute article
    - Rogue, "Hey Look", December 1965 (Box MLM 20, Item 9)
    - Saturday Evening Post, "MAD: Wild Oracle of the Teenage Underground", December 21, 1963 (Box MLM 26, Item 9)
      General article about MAD with two photographs of MAD staff
    - Scene, August 1958 (Box MLM 26, Item 10)
    - Scene, "The MAD Show", February 26- March 4, 1967 (Box MLM 20, Item 10)
    - Scholastic Search, May 1989 (Box MLM 20, Item 11)
      Cover illustration, man holding MAD magazine
    - Scholastic Scope, "Scope Visits MAD Magazine (Big Deal), April 2, 1973 (Box MLM 20, Item 12)
      Alfred E. Neuman on cover
    - Screw, "No More Gaines", June 22, 1992 (Box MLM 26, Item 11)
      EC parody cover; editorial tribute to William M. Gaines; print of August 1988 interview with Gaines
    - Soda Net, July 1992 (Box MLM 20, Item 13)
      Letter from PSBCA member discussing Completely MAD book with reference to Happy Jack and Cherry Sparkle soads featuring Alfred E. Neuman.
    - Soda Net, November 1992 (Box MLM 20, Item 14)
      Michael Lerner letter in this issue
    - Spin Again, "Mad about MAD", 1993 (Box MLM 20, Item 15)
      MAD Collectibles
    - Spin, "Comics", August 1988 (Box MLM 27, Frame 1)
      EC and MAD discussed in an article about comics
    - Sports Illustrated, September 23, 1991 (Box MLM 20, Item 16)
      Alfred E. Neuman on page 29.
    - Spy, "485 Madison Ave", January- February 1991 (Box MLM 20, Item 17)
      Article about Gaines and the 300th issue cover change
    - Spy, December 1991 (Box MLM 20, Item 18)
      MAD book advertisement
    - Tennis, "Around the World with the Tennis Zanies of MAD", July 1979 (Box MLM 21, Item 1)
      Articel about MAD by Nick Meglin
    - Terminal City, "Wot??? Me Worry?", March 20, 1998 (Box MLM 27, Item 2)
      Alfred E. Neuman caricature on cover.
    - Texas Monthly, "What, Me President? How Perot Can Win", June 1992 (Box MLM 21, Item 2)
      H. Ross Perot as Alfred E. Neuman
    - Tikkun, "Of Mice and Menschen: Jewish Comics Come of Age", March- April 1992 (Box MLM 21, Item 3)
      Overview of Jewish influence on comics with MAD; with illustrations.
    - Time, "Sassy Newcomer", September 24, 1956 (Box MLM 21, Item 4)
      Article about Playboy which has reference to MAD as "a short lived satirical pulp."
    - Time, "MADdiction", July 7, 1958 (Box MLM 21, Item 5)
      Article about the early MAD craze; with photographs of William Gaines
    - Time, "The Best Things in Life are Free", April 3, 1964 (Box MLM 21, Item 6)
      Article about the Irving Berlin/ MAD lawsuit
    - Time, "Life Imitates Art", December 18, 1964 (Box MLM 21, Item 7)
      One line reference to MAD in an article about Art Buchwald
    - Time, "All Jaw, No Teeth", Undated (Box MLM 21, Item 8)
      The MAD Show review
    - Time, February 10, 1986 (Box MLM 21, Item 9)
      MAD reference
    - Time, December 30, 1991 (Box MLM 21, Item 10)
      Capsulized review from the December 9, 1991 issue
    - Time, "A Perfect MAS Man", June 15, 1992 (Box MLM 21, Item 11)
    - Time, "Milestones", March 8, 1993 (Box MLM 21, Item 12)
    - Time, "What's Hot, Doc? Retail!", May 9, 1994 (Box MLM 21, Item 13)
      Article about Warner Bros. store with mention of MAD products.
    - Time, March 9, 1998 (Box MLM 21, Item 14)
      Antonio Prohias, sketches Spy Vs. Spy, obituary
    - Time, June 8, 1998 (Box MLM 21, Item 15)
      Reference to Harvey Kurtzman's MAD comic
    - Time, January 17, 2000 (Box MLM 21, Item 16)
    - Time Out New York, "What, We Worry?", April 3-10, 1997 (Box MLM 21, Item 17)
      Relaunch of MAD
    - Today's Collector, Febraury 1996 (Box MLM 27, Item 3)
    - Today's Collector, "Cashing in on MAD Memorabilia", June 1996 (Box MLM 27, Item 4)
    - Today's Collector, "Fun and Games", September 1998 (Box MLM 27, Item 5)
      MAD Board game.
    - Tops, March 1954 (Box MLM 22, Item 1)
      Bill Gaines profiles
    - Toy Collector and Price Guide, December 1995 (Box MLM 22, Item 2)
      Brief mention about 4th annual MAD Auction
    - Toy Fare, May 1999 (Box MLM 22, Item 3)
      MAD Trivia Contest, page 82
    - Toy Shop, March 29, 1996 (Box MLM 27, Item 5)
    - Toy Shop, April 26, 1996 (Box MLM 27, Item 6)
    - Trading Cards, January 1993 (Box MLM 22, Item 4)
    - The Triangle Comic Review, November 4, 1992 (Box MLM 27, Item 8)
    - True West, August 1956 (Box MLM 22, Item 5)
      Jack Davis cover illustration and the cowboy from MAD #20
    - TV Guide, October 31- November 6, 1959 (Box MLM 22, Item 6)
    - TV Guide, February 20-26, 1960 (Box MLM 22, Item 7)
      TV special featuring MAD segment
    - TV Guide, "MAD about Television", Ocotber 26- November 1, 1968 (Box MLM 22, Item 8)
      Article about MAD parodies of TV with examples
    - TV Guide, December 28, 1991 (Box MLM 22, Item 9)
      John Goodman quotes "Potrzebie" and mentions MAD in the interview
    - TV Guide, "Lighten up, Letterman", January 4-10, 1992 (Box MLM 22, Item 10)
      From the article: "He may look like MAD Magazine's Alfred E. Neuman, but he sure doesn't follow the latter's motto: What, me Worry?"
    - TV Guide, "MAD About You", July 3- August 6, 1993 (Box MLM 22, Item 11)
      Brief mention about first MAD "Big Question" survey.
    - TV Guide, Ocotber 14- 22, 1995 (Box MLM 22, Item 12)
      MAD TV mentioned in "Cheers & Jeers" column; Alfred E. Neuman look-a-like contest; Closeup of premiere episode of MAD TV; Full page ad for MAD.
    - TV Guide, "Saturday Night Showdown", November 25- December 1, 1995 (Box MLM 22, Item 13)
      Article about Saturday Night Live and MAD TV fighting it our for the Saturday night viewing audience; with color photograph of MAD TV cast.
    - TV guide, "Getting MAD...Again", May 25- 31, 1996 (Box MLM 23, Item 1)
      Article on MAD TV show.
    - Tuff Stuff's Collect!, March 1998 (Box MLM 23, Item 2)
      Price guide for MAD Magazines
    - U. The National College Magzine, "What, SNL Worry?", November 1995 (Box MLM 27, Item 9)
      Article on MAD TV with color photographs of cast.
    - Upside, "What, Me Worry?", November 1997 (Box MLM 23, Item 3)
      Bill Gates as Alfred E. Neuman on cover.
    - U.S. News & World Reports, "People", June 15, 1992 (Box MLM 23, Item 4)
      William Gaines Obituary.
    - U.S. News & World Reports, "Harvey Kurtzman", March 8, 1993 (Box MLM 23, Item 5)
      Harvey Kurtzman Obituary.
    - Wired, "Spy vs Nerd!", June 1994 (Box MLM 23, Item 6)
      Spy vs Spy cover illustration.
    - Writer's Digest, "Scripting for the Comic Books", August 1953 (Box MLM 23, Item 7)
      William Gaines is quoted.
    - Writer's Digest, "Madman Gaines Pleads for Plots", February 1954 (Box MLM 23, Item 7)